Charlie Seemann collection of photographs of vaqueros and gauchos
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Charlie Seemann collection of photographs of vaqueros and gauchos 1985-1986
AFC 2018/001
399 items.
374 photographs: color slides; 35mm.
1 folder.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
From November 2-13, 1985, folklorist Charlie Seemann led a group of six volunteers for the California-based Center for Field Research to document vaqueros in the Concepción area of Paraguay and a horse trading operation near Asunción. Photographs documented vaqueros at work, their dress, horses, cattle, gear, and saddles. Additionally, Seemann documented the estancia haciendas, ranch buildings, corrals and fencing, landscapes, and ranch life (175 color slides from Paraguay). From September 12-25, 1986, Charlie Seemann led a similar trip to document guachos in Uruguay at the Estancia San Pedro de Timote, and near Melo, Uruguay. This group traveled to Bagé, in southern Brazil, to observe and document the Dia Do Gaúcho festival, started in 1848 to commemorate the gaúchos who fought in Guerra Dos Farrapos, or War of the Rags. The festival included a parade of some 3,000 mounted gaúchos, music, food, dance, and an outdoor Catholic mass for mounted gaúchos (60 color slides from Brazil). The group returned to Paysandú, Uruguay, and documented the estancia of Hubert Maness, Los Mortreros, near Mercedes on the Rio Negro (138 total color slides from Uruguay). The collection includes Charlie Seemann's original field notes (25 pages).
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Seemann, Charlie, photographer.
Subjects
Cowboys--Brazil--Bagé--Photographs.; Cowboys--Paraguay--Social life and customs.; Cowboys--Uruguay--Photographs.; Festivals--Brazil--Bagé--Photographs.; Parades--Brazil--Bagé--Photographs.; Ranches--Paraguay--Photographs.; Ranches--Uruguay--Photographs.; Ranching--Paraguay--Photographs.; Ranching--Uruguay--Photographs.
Places
Asunción (Paraguay)--Social life and customs.; Bagé (Brazil)--Social life and customs.; Cerro Largo (Uruguay)--Social life and customs.; Concepción (Paraguay)--Social life and customs.; Paysandú (Uruguay)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Documentary photography.; Ethnography.; Field notes.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: 1. Field notes; 2. Paraguay photographs; 3. Uruguay photographs; 4. Brazil photographs.
Acquisition
Charles Seemann; 2017.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research; access to collection materials may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Electronic Format
Digital surrogates of manuscript materials (25 pages) are available.
Biographical Note
Charlie Seemann is a former executive director of the Western Folklife Center in Elko, Nevada, and a former member of the American Folklife Center Board of Trustees. He holds an M.A. in folklife studies from the University of California, Los Angeles and has served extensively as a folklorist including at the Country Music Foundation, the American Folklife Center, and the National Council for the Traditional Arts. He is the co-editor of the book Folklife and Museums: Selected Readings and has produced and/or annotated more than 30 documentary albums of folk, country, and cowboy music. In 1983, he received a Wrangler Award from the National Cowboy Hall of Fame and Western Heritage Museum and a Grammy nomination for the New World Records anthology Back in the Saddle Again: American Cowboy Songs. In 2003 he received a second Wrangler award for producing Buck Ramsey: Hittin' the Trail. He has written numerous articles on western culture and cowboy music.
Scope and Content
From November 2-13, 1985, folklorist Charlie Seemann led a group of six volunteers for the California-based Center for Field Research to document vaqueros in the Concepción area of Paraguay and a horse trading operation near Asunción. Photographs documented vaqueros at work, their dress, horses, cattle, gear, and saddles. Additionally, Seemann documented the estancia haciendas, ranch buildings, corrals and fencing, landscapes, and ranch life (175 color slides from Paraguay). From September 12-25, 1986, Charlie Seemann led a similar trip to document guachos in Uruguay at the Estancia San Pedro de Timote, and near Melo, Uruguay. This group traveled to Bagé, in southern Brazil, to observe and document the Dia Do Gaúcho festival, started in 1848 to commemorate the gaúchos who fought in Guerra Dos Farrapos, or War of the Rags. The festival included a parade of some 3,000 mounted gaúchos, music, food, dance, and an outdoor Catholic mass for mounted gaúchos (60 color slides from Brazil). The group returned to Paysandú, Uruguay, and documented the estancia of Hubert Maness, Los Mortreros, near Mercedes on the Rio Negro (138 total color slides from Uruguay). The collection includes Charlie Seemann's original field notes (25 pages).
Container List
- Series 1: Field notes, 1985-1986, 25 manuscript pages in one folder
  - Vaquero of Paraguay Expedition: Summary Report, November 2-13, 1985, 5 pages (Container 1)
  - Field Journal Summary - 1986 Gaucho Expedition, 1986, 20 pages (Container 1)
- Series 2: Paraguay photographs, November 1985, 176 slides: color; 35mm
  Titles for each slide were provided by the photographer.
  - Pier in Asuncion on Paraguay river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_001 (Box 1)
  - Transport ship to Concepcion, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_002 (Box 1)
  - Transport ship, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_003 (Box 1)
  - Ship schedule, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_004 (Box 1)
  - Map of Paraguay, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_005 (Box 1)
  - Map of Paraguay, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_006 (Box 1)
  - Loading gear onto boat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_007 (Box 1)
  - Loading gear, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_008 (Box 1)
  - Cattle barge on river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_009 (Box 1)
  - Barn at Estancia San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_010 (Box 1)
  - Boat used to take vehicles across river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_011 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero with horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_012 (Box 1)
  - Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_013 (Box 1)
  - Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_014 (Box 1)
  - Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_015 (Box 1)
  - Branding horses at horse ranch outside of Asuncsion, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_016 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros at corral at horse ranch, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_017 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero with horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_018 (Box 1)
  - Branding colt, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_019 (Box 1)
  - Branding colt, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_020 (Box 1)
  - Loading VW van onto raft/boat for transport across river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_021 (Box 1)
  - Transport boat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_022 (Box 1)
  - Unloading van from raft/boat with van across river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_023 (Box 1)
  - Young men poling boat with van across river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_024 (Box 1)
  - Poling across river, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_025 (Box 1)
  - Road from river inland to Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_026 (Box 1)
  - Fence, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_027 (Box 1)
  - Fence, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_028 (Box 1)
  - Horse shoots at horse ranch near Asuncion, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_029 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating horses, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_030 (Box 1)
  - Horse corral, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_031 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating horses, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_032 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero at vaccination chute, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_033 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_034 (Box 1)
  - Doctoring horses in vaccination chute, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_035 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros taking a break to drink maté, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_036 (Box 1)
  - Roping young horses for branding, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_037 (Box 1)
  - Roping horses, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_038 (Box 1)
  - Kitchen at Ranch San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_039 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_040 (Box 1)
  - Mounted vaquero, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_041 (Box 1)
  - Roping from mule, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_042 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_043 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with calf, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_044 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with calf, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_045 (Box 1)
  - Zebu cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_046 (Box 1)
  - Military transport plane we flew on, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_047 (Box 1)
  - Zebu cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_048 (Box 1)
  - Saddle mules, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_049 (Box 1)
  - Zebu cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_050 (Box 1)
  - "runway" for military transport plane, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_051 (Box 1)
  - Moving zebu cattle in corrals, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_052 (Box 1)
  - Zebu cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_053 (Box 1)
  - Military transport plane, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_054 (Box 1)
  - Fence at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_055 (Box 1)
  - Barn at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_056 (Box 1)
  - Barn at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_057 (Box 1)
  - Runway for transport plane, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_058 (Box 1)
  - Woman making nañuti lace, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_059 (Box 1)
  - Woman with nañuti lace, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_060 (Box 1)
  - Ranch workers playing music at asada after work, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_061 (Box 1)
  - Interior of bunkhouse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_062 (Box 1)
  - Family at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_063 (Box 1)
  - Family at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_064 (Box 1)
  - Animal pens, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_065 (Box 1)
  - Drying jerky, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_066 (Box 1)
  - Butchering goat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_067 (Box 1)
  - Asada, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_068 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros weighing cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_069 (Box 1)
  - Playing music with Paraguayan musicians, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_070 (Box 1)
  - Butchering goat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_071 (Box 1)
  - Butchering goat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_072 (Box 1)
  - Butchering goat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_073 (Box 1)
  - Skinning goat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_074 (Box 1)
  - Cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_075 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero herding cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_076 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_077 (Box 1)
  - Butchering goat, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_078 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero with cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_079 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero in corral, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_080 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros branding colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_081 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero roping colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_082 (Box 1)
  - Roping colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_083 (Box 1)
  - Branding colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_084 (Box 1)
  - Branding colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_085 (Box 1)
  - Branding colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_086 (Box 1)
  - Branding colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_087 (Box 1)
  - Branding colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_088 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_089 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_090 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_091 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_092 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_093 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_094 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_095 (Box 1)
  - Vaccinating colts, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_096 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero swimming with his horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_097 (Box 1)
  - Barn at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_098 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with prized quarter horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_099 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with quarter horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_100 (Box 1)
  - Running cattle through medicinal dip bath, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_101 (Box 1)
  - Medicinal dip bath chute, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_102 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros lining up horses and mules for morning saddling, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_103 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros lining up horses and mules for morning saddling, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_104 (Box 1)
  - Cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_105 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_106 (Box 1)
  - Moving cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_107 (Box 1)
  - Fence at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_108 (Box 1)
  - Cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_109 (Box 1)
  - Cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_110 (Box 1)
  - Charlie Seemann, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_111 (Box 1)
  - Charlie Seemann, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_112 (Box 1)
  - Road, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_113 (Box 1)
  - Ox cart, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_114 (Box 1)
  - Ox cart, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_115 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_116 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_117 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_118 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_119 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_120 (Box 1)
  - Interior of chapel at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_121 (Box 1)
  - Interior of chapel at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_122 (Box 1)
  - Ranch house/hacienda at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_123 (Box 1)
  - Hacienda at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_124 (Box 1)
  - Training young oxen to yoke, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_125 (Box 1)
  - Water tower, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_126 (Box 1)
  - Chapel at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_127 (Box 1)
  - Interior of chapel at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_128 (Box 1)
  - Training young oxen to yoke, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_129 (Box 1)
  - Training young oxen to yoke, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_130 (Box 1)
  - Training young oxen to yoke, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_131 (Box 1)
  - Tree blossoms, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_132 (Box 1)
  - Using tractor engine to grind grain, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_133 (Box 1)
  - Using tractor engine to grind grain, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_134 (Box 1)
  - Training young oxen to yoke, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_135 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros in horse corral, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_136 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros in horse corral, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_137 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros in horse corral, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_138 (Box 1)
  - Using tractor engine to grind grain, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_139 (Box 1)
  - Saddled Criollo horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_140 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros relaxing at the barn for lunch, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_141 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_142 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero braiding a leather reata, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_143 (Box 1)
  - Vaquero saddle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_144 (Box 1)
  - Saddle with sheepskin, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_145 (Box 1)
  - Saddle with sheepskin, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_146 (Box 1)
  - Horse with headgear, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_147 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with horses, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_148 (Box 1)
  - Interior of bunkhouse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_149 (Box 1)
  - Interior of bunkhouse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_150 (Box 1)
  - Hacienda Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_151 (Box 1)
  - Bathroom, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_152 (Box 1)
  - Batteries for electricity, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_153 (Box 1)
  - Sitting room, hacienda Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_154 (Box 1)
  - Bedroom, hacienda at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_155 (Box 1)
  - Tree arbor, hacienda at Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_156 (Box 1)
  - Dining room, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_157 (Box 1)
  - Kitchen, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_158 (Box 1)
  - Kitchen, Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_159 (Box 1)
  - Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_160 (Box 1)
  - Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_161 (Box 1)
  - Water tanks, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_162 (Box 1)
  - Emu, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_163 (Box 1)
  - Interior of chapel, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_164 (Box 1)
  - Kitchen, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_165 (Box 1)
  - Log feeding trough, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_166 (Box 1)
  - Log feeding trough, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_167 (Box 1)
  - Braided headstall, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_168 (Box 1)
  - Interior of horse gear store, Asuncion, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_169 (Box 1)
  - Interior of horse gear store, Asuncion, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_170 (Box 1)
  - Roping from mule, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_171 (Box 1)
  - Fence, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_172 (Box 1)
  - Criollo horse, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_173 (Box 1)
  - Vaqueros with cattle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_174 (Box 1)
  - The "Capitán," or foreman, of Rancho San Fernando, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_175 (Box 1)
  - Saddle, November 1985, AFC 2018/001: p_176 (Box 1)
- Series 3: Uruguay photographs, September 1986, 138 slides: color; 35mm
  - Gauchos castrating calf, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_001 (Box 1)
  - Hacienda, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_002 (Box 1)
  - Mounted gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_003 (Box 1)
  - Hacienda, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_004 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho with horses, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_005 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_006 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_007 (Box 1)
  - Gauchos herding cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_008 (Box 1)
  - Local "whiskeria," or bar, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_009 (Box 1)
  - Local cemetery, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_010 (Box 1)
  - Alter at cemetery, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_011 (Box 1)
  - Old custom house in Puerto de Chuy, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_012 (Box 1)
  - Stone bridge at customs house, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_013 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho's residence on Estancia, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_014 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho herding cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_015 (Box 1)
  - Sheep barn at Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_016 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_017 (Box 1)
  - Ranch building, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_018 (Box 1)
  - Ranch truck, Estancia Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_019 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_020 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_021 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_022 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_023 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_024 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_025 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_026 (Box 1)
  - Breaking horse to ride, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_027 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho working leather reata on fence wire, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_028 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho working leather reata on fence wire, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_029 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho throwing lasso, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_030 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho's belt, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_031 (Box 1)
  - Hacienda and windmill, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_032 (Box 1)
  - Bell tower, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_033 (Box 1)
  - Gaucho showing quarter horse, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_034 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho showing quarter horse, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_035 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho showing quarter horse, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_036 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho showing quarter horse, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_037 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho showing quarter horse, Los Morteros, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_038 (Box 2)
  - Horses, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_039 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho putting on spurs, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_040 (Box 2)
  - Road, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_041 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos with cattle, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_042 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos with cattle, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_043 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos with cattle, Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_044 (Box 2)
  - Volunteers in transport truck, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_045 (Box 2)
  - Mounted gauchos, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_046 (Box 2)
  - Horse with head gear, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_047 (Box 2)
  - Horse with head gear, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_048 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_049 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_050 (Box 2)
  - Children at Estancia San Pedro de Timote, Cerro Colorado, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_051 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho chasing cow, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_052 (Box 2)
  - Interior of "pulperia" or bar, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_053 (Box 2)
  - Castrating calf, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_054 (Box 2)
  - Castrating calves, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_055 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_056 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_057 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_058 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_059 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos moving sheep, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_060 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_061 (Box 2)
  - Stone fence post, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_062 (Box 2)
  - Stone fence post, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_063 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_064 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_065 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_066 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_067 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_068 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_069 (Box 2)
  - Gaucho with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_070 (Box 2)
  - Gauchos with cattle, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_071 (Box 2)
  - Castrating calf, September 1986, AFC 2018/001: u_072 (Box 2)